McCulloch, Frank Papers 5883
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series SERIES V: TEACHING MATERIALS
  - Interim Report and Recommendations of the Chairman's Task Force on the NLRB for 1976 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    November 5, 1976 (2 copies)
  - Institute for Southern Studies. "'Here Come a Wind'/Labor on the Move.", 1976 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    Southern Exposure Vol. IV, No. 1-2
  - Committee for Economic Development. Improving Labor Relations and Personnel Management in State and Local Government, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    Draft of policy statement for discussion by the Subcommittee on Government Productivity and Labor Relations at October 6, 1977 meeting. September 1977
- Series SERIES VI: ADMINISTRATIVE AND PERSONNEL FILES
  - Administrative - General, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Includes: memoranda re: various changes in administrative practices and procedures at the NLRB
  - Administrative Conference of the United States - General, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 2-3)
    Includes: list of members, committee assignments, bylaws and proposed bylaws, survey of recommendations from previous conferences, press releases, correspondence, "Pending Proposals to Amend the Federal Administration Procedure Act: an Analysis of S. 518." Administrative Law Review, March 1968
  - Administrative Conference of the United States - General, 1969-1970 (Box 23, Folder 4-5)
    Includes: list of members of the conference; memoranda from the Chairman of the conference, Jerre S. Williams
  - Administrative Conference of the United States - General, 1971-1974 (Box 23, Folder 6-7)
    Includes: 1970-1971 report: administrative conference of the United States (July 1971); Recommendations 23-26; news
  - Administrative Conference of the United States - Summary Judgment and Discovery in Agency Adjudication, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 8-9)
    Includes: Recommendations C and D discussed by the Administrative Conference Assembly on June 2-3, 1970; handwritten notes; correspondence; consultant's report in support of the recommendations of the committee
  - Administrative Conference of the United States - Summary Judgment in Agency Adjudication, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    Includes: Recommendation C discussed by the Committee on Agency Organization and Procedure, motion for decision, report
  - Administrative Conference of the United States - Hearing Examiners, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 11-12)
    Includes: report, summary of survey responses and draft recommendations prepared for the Committee on Personnel prepared by professor Robert Park; recommendations re: change of hearing examiner title, recruitment and selection, training and continuing education; testimony of George Bokat
  - Administrative Conference of the United States - Title Change for Trial/Hearing Examiners, 1965-1969 (Box 23, Folder 13-14)
    Includes: correspondence between Frank McCulloch and the Federal Trial Examiners' Conference; Recommendation H of the Personnel Committee, September 1969; materials supporting the title change
  - Administrative Conference of the United States - Civil Service Determinations, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    Includes: memorandum re: materials relating to "Judicial Review of Civil Service Determinations," from Roger C. Cramton to the members of the Committee on Judicial Review; handwritten notes.
  - Administrative Conference of the United States - Judicial Review Committee, 1966-1968 (Box 23, Folder 16-18)
    Includes: minutes and notes from Committee meetings; correspondence; memoranda; American Bar Association reports on labor relations law
  - Administrative Conference of the United States - Judicial Review Committee (Forum Shopping), 1968 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    Includes: statistics, notes, correspondence
  - Administrative Conference of the United States - Miscellaneous, 1971-1972 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    Includes: Cramton, Roger. "The Why, Where, and How of Broadened Public Participation in the Administrative Process." Remarks prepared for the Administrative Process Symposium. Georgetown University Law Center, Washington, DC. 17 Sept. 1971.: notices of sessions
  - Amendments to the Administrative Procedures Act (APA), 1964-1967 (Box 23, Folder 21-22)
    Includes: S. 518, introduced 1/19/67; S. 518, A Bill to Amend to Administrative Procedure Act. Statement of Frank McCulloch before the Senate Subcommittee on Administrative Practice and Procedure, Washington, DC. March 17.; early APA reports
  - Appropriations - Appeal to White House, 1969-1971 (Box 23, Folder 23-24)
    Includes: National Labor Relations Board Budget; materials expressing concern for the impact of budget cuts in Fiscal year 1971; letter to the White House from Frank McCulloch re: request for reconsideration of appropriations for FY 1971; similar appeal from Secretary of Labor to the Bureau of the Budget; correspondence re: staffing concerns in Region 19; other supporting materials
  - Appropriations - Fiscal Year 1970, 1968-1970 (Box 23, Folder 25-27)
    Includes: fiscal data, memoranda, case statistics, notes, statements of Frank McCulloch and Arnold Ordman before the Senate Committee on Appropriations (August 6, 1969), statements of Frank McCulloch and Arnold Ordman before the House Committee on Appropriations (April 15,1969), Justification of Appropriations Estimates for Fiscal Year 1970, National Labor Relations Board; agenda for NLRB Budget Hearing (Nov. 4,1968), correspondence, 1969-1970 program review, 1969 operating plan and 1970 budget request
  - Appropriations - Fiscal Year 1971, 1970-1971 (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
    Includes fiscal data, memoranda, case statistics, statements of Edward Miller and Arnold Ordman before the Senate Committee on Appropriations (June 25, 1970), statements of Frank McCulloch and Arnold Ordman before the House Committee on Appropriations (May 21, 1970), Justification of Appropriations Estimates for Fiscal Year 1971, National Labor Relations Board; agenda for briefing re: House Appropriations Hearing
  - Appropriations - Fiscal Year 1972-1973 (Box 24, Folder 3-4)
    Includes: Justification of Appropriations Estimates for Fiscal Year 1973 (House and Senate), National Labor Relations Board; House Hearings on NLRB, 1972
  - Ethics - Conflicts of Interest, 1961-1962 (Box 24, Folder 5-6)
    Includes: text of Executive Order 11222 from the Federal Register; other Executive Orders and legislation; memoranda from the White House to the heads of Executive Departments and Agencies - "Preventing Conflicts of Interest on the Part of Advisors and Consultants to the Government," (February 1962) and "Standards of Conduct for Civilian Employees," (July 1961); excerpts from NLRB Manual (R 8-11-54).
  - Executive and Legislative Branch Contacts, 1963-1968 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    Includes: Draft of McCulloch's announcement of his resignation from the position of Chairman of the NLRB to the President; memoranda from McCulloch to the President(1963) in response to inquiries from the President; memorandum from President Johnson to all heads of departments and agencies (1968); notes on correspondence with Congressman Pucinski re: trucking strike in Chicago (May 1967) and lockout of dairy workers by a Chicago Dairy; correspondence with various Congressmen re: general personnel issues (i.e. endorsement of candidate for a Regional Director position)
  - Memoranda - Miscellaneous Administrative Issues (Box 24, Folder 8-9)
    Includes: racketeering, delays in NLRB proceedings, unit determination, judicial review of internal procedures of decision-making, Regional Information Program, participation in NLRB processes, etc.
  - National Labor Relations Board Professional Association, 1961-1968 (Box 24, Folder 10-11)
    Includes: Agreement between the National Labor Relations Board and the NLRB Professional Association (signed December 17, 1964); Agreements between the General Counsel of the NLRB and the NLRB Union (signed March 14, 1966, June 21, 1968); Minutes and handwritten notes from meetings between the Association and the NLRB; memoranda re: various proposals and counter-proposals, certification and determination of appropriate unit, request for recognition; advisory arbitration between the General Counsel of the NLRB, the NLRB Union, the NLRB Field Attorneys Association and Local No. 4, Independent (October-November 1963); A policy For Employee-Management Cooperation in the Federal Service. (1961, November 30). Report of the President's Task Force on Employee-Management Relations in the Federal Service.
  - National Labor Relations Board Professional Association, 1969-1970 (Box 24, Folder 12-15)
    Includes: briefs for the arbitration of grievance submitted by Amadeo Greco (1970); agreement between the NLRB and the NLRB Professional Association (signed Oct. 1969); agreement between the General Counsel of the NLRB and the NLRB Professional Association (signed Oct. 1969); agreement between the NLRB and the NLRB Union and its Washington Local for clerical employees (signed July 3, 1969); news articles; correspondence and memoranda re: seeking mediation due to impasse in bargaining, promotions
  - Operations, 1966-1969 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    Includes: Administrative problems of the Board. Statement of Frank McCulloch before the Special Subcommittee on Labor of the Committee on Education and Labor, US House of Representatives, Washington, DC. February 9.; McCulloch's reply to inquiries from Senator Edward Kennedy re: citizen involvement in the administrative processes of the NLRB; "Disposition Pattern For ULP Cases," chart comparing Fiscal year 1968 with Fiscal year 1967 and 1969
  - Operations - General Counsel's Summary, 1966-1969 (Box 24, Folder 17-18)
    Includes: Office of the General Counsel, National Labor Relations Board. Summary of Operations. Fiscal year 1968 and 1969 (six month), Fiscal year 1967 and 1968 (six months), Fiscal year 1966 and 1967 (six month); statistics on enforcement and review cases decided by the Circuit Courts of Appeals for Fiscal Year 1969
  - Personnel - General (Box 24, Folder 19-21)
    Includes: Information cards for Regional Directors; minutes of meetings; reviews and proposed revisions to NLRB Administrative Policies and Procedures Manual; information and plans re: Equal Employment Opportunity; information re: youth in the Federal Service - trainee programs; materials re: "Employee Responsibilities and Conduct"; procedures for developing policy with an employee organization acting as the exclusive representative of employees
  - Plans and Proposals - Information Program, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    Includes: A Prospectus for an Expanded Information Program For the National Labor Relations Board [Draft]. Submitted for consideration in June 1963 - Noted by McCulloch as "Rothman Suggestions"
  - Plans and Proposals - Miscellaneous (Box 24, Folder 23-25)
    Includes: administrative agendas; memoranda re: productivity and case load (backlogs), clarification of certification proceedings, summary judgment, public advisory committees, continuous board agenda; administrative agendas
  - Plans and Proposals - Security Program (Box 24, Folder 26)
    Includes: recommendations from the President for the Federal employee security program through Executive Order 10450, information from Civil Service Commission
  - Review of Executive Secretary's Office, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 27)
    Includes: re-evaluation of functions, structure, grades; request from Ogden Fields for Board approval of personnel actions in the Office of the Executive Secretary
  - Staffing (Box 24, Folder 28)
    Includes: Applicant materials, notes from interviews, breakdown of applicant qualifications
  - Statutory Administrative Procedures., 1967 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    Includes: Examples of Federal Agencies other than the NLRB that have statutory administrative responsibilities; United States. Department of Justice. Attorney General's Memorandum on the Public Information Section of the Administrative Procedure Act. Washington: GPO
- Series SERIES VII: PHOTOGRAPHS AND AUDIO TAPES
  - McCulloch, Frank. "The National Labor Relations Act at Age 35: Some Comments on the Law and the Changing Labor Relations Scene.", 1970 (Box 25, Folder 1-27)
  - Mrs. McCulloch (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - Audio Tape - Employer Anti-Union Appeal, 1964 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    Noted as: "Pharmaseal Record. Mailed to employees homes just ahead of NLRB election. Record dated March 17, 1964."
  - Audio Tape - Farewell Lunch for Frank McCulloch, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 30)
    Includes speech by Lane Kirkland
  - Album - Frank McCulloch Becomes Chairman of the National Labor Relations Board, 1961 (Box 25, Folder 31)
    March 7, 1961. Presented to Frank McCulloch on behalf of the staff of the National Labor Relations Board. Includes NLRB Bulletin (text) and photographs